Guide to the Nevins & Townsend Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Nevins and Townsend papers
1816-1858
MS 1179
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
12
(14 boxes)
Letterbooks (1833-1847), ledgers, and other account books (1817-1848) of Nevins and Townsend, a brokerage firm in New York City.
Nevins and Townsend
Arrangement
The papers are arranged by record type.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
In part, transferred from the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, 1984.
Scope and Contents
Letterbooks (1833-1847), ledgers, and other account books (1817-1848) of Nevins and Townsend, a brokerage firm in New York City.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Business; New York (State); Account books; Brokers; Nevins, David H.; Nevins, Russel H.; Townsend, Elihu; Nevins and Townsend
- Inventory, 1816 - 1858
  - Letterbooks
    - Incoming letters
      - 1845 Apr -1846 Jun (Box 1)
      - 1847 Feb -Aug (Box 1)
    - Outgoing letters
      - 1833 Nov -1836 Mar (Box 1)
      - 1836 Mar -1837 Dec (Box 7)
      - 1837 Dec -1839 Apr (Box 7)
      - 1839 Apr -1840 Apr; loose index laid in (Box 8)
      - 1836 Apr -1841 Aug; with some accounts (Box 1)
    - Ledgers recording correspondence and receipts
      - [1843?] Sep -[1844?] Dec (Box 1)
      - 1845 Jan -1847 May (Box 1)
    - Stock Journals
      - 1817 Oct -1818 Apr (Box 1)
      - 1830 Jun -1831 Jun (Box 2)
      - 1834 Jul -1835 Jul (Box 2)
      - 1835 Jul -1836 Jan (Box 2)
      - 1836 Feb -Jul (Box 2)
      - 1838 Feb -Jul (Box 2)
      - 1839 Feb -Jul (Box 2)
      - 1839 Jul -1840 Apr (Box 2)
      - 1842 Jul -1843 Jan (Box 9)
      - 1845 Jul -1846 Jan (Box 9)
      - 1848 Jan -Jul (Box 9)
      - 1849 Jan -Jul, Oct (Box 9)
      - 1850 Jan -Nov (Box 9)
      - 1851 May -Oct (Box 9)
      - 1852 Sep -1853 Feb; pen laid in (Box 10)
      - 1853 Feb -Aug (Box 10)
      - 1853 Aug -1854 Feb (Box 10)
    - Day books of stock transactions
      - 1834 Nov -1836 May (Box 3)
      - 1836 May -1838 Sep (Box 3)
      - 1838 Sep -1841 Nov (Box 3)
      - 1841 Nov -1850 Mar (Box 3)
    - Day books
      - 1816 Jan -1822 Apr; missing pages at end (Box 3)
      - 1837 Apr -1838 Jan (Box 3)
      - 1842 Sep -1843 Jul (Box 3)
      - 1845 Sep - 1850 Mar ("Merchants") (Box 3)
      - 1856 May -1858 Nov (Box 11)
    - Day books of check received ("Notes and Drafts Lodged for Collection")
      - 1837 Mar -1839 Mar (Box 12)
      - 1840 Apr -1841 Jun (Box 3)
      - 1841 Jun -1844 Sep (Box 12)
      - 1844 Sep -1846 Nov (Box 12)
      - 1846 Nov -1850 Apr (Box 13)
      - 1843 Aug -1847 Dec (Box 13)
    - "Contract Register" ledgers
      - 1836 Mar -1839 Dec (Box 4)
      - 1838 Nov -1839 Oct (Box 4)
    - Stock ledgers
      - 1834 Nov - 1835 Dec ("A") (Box 4)
      - 1835 Dec - 1838 Sep ("B") (Box 5)
      - 1838 Sep - 1844 Feb ("C") (Box 5)
      - 1844 Feb - 1850 Mar ("D"); loose index laid in (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous ledgers and account books
      - 1818 Mar -1820 Jan (Box 6)
      - 1825 Jan - 1832 Oct ("Bills Receivable") (Box 6)
      - 1832 Jun -1835 Dec (Box 6)
      - 1833 Feb - 1844 Apr ("D") (Box 14)
      - 1837 Jan -1844 Apr (Box 6)
      - 1838 Mar -Sep (Box 6)
      - 1838 Aug -1841 May; pages missing at end (Box 6)
      - 1841 Nov -1842 Sep (Box 6)
      - [1844] May -1849 May (Box 6)
      - 1844 -1850 Feb (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous
      - 1835 May - 1841 Jan ("Balances") (Box 6)
      - 1835 May - 1842 Oct ("Interest Book") (Box 14)
      - 1839 Apr - 1843 Dec ("Bill Book") (Box 6)
      - [1846?] ("Bill Book") (Box 6)
      - [1844 - 1848?] ("Cancellations") (Box 6)